https://dbsdata.co.uk/privacy-policy-commercial-relationships/

Data & SolutionsFull Service Direct MailB2B MarketingB2C MarketingData CleanseCleanseVerifyEnhanceData AnalyticsData ComplianceCampaign DeliveryMarket ResearchAbout UsHistory & CultureMeet the TeamOur ComplianceJoin UsResourcesBlogCase StudiesEventsPressVideosWhite PapersData SheetsNewsContact UsEnquiriesRemove My DetailsPanel Login
Call Back Request
Home > Privacy Policy – Commercial RelationshipsPrivacy Policy – Commercial RelationshipsDatamarketing Ltd “DBS” registered in England and Wales under company registration number 6394529, our registered office is at 1 Buckingham Court, Dairy Road, Chelmsford, CM2 6XW.We are also members of the Data and Marketing Association and registered with the Information Commissioners Office, our data protection registration number is Z8475760.Operating as DBS Datamarketing and DBS Data, we are a data solutions business working with marketing services organisations, media agencies, brokers and brands.You can contact us by phone on 01245 397 570 where you can speak to The Compliance Department or email complianceteam@dbsdata.co.uk with your questions.This policy relates to you if you visit our website, you apply to work with us, if you are a client, supplier, partner or enquirer, or if you are attending one of our events. It also applies to you if we have approached you regarding our services or if we have acquired your details through events, networking or a referral. ContentsThis Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect directly from you, receive from or share with third parties about you. It also explains how we’ll store and handle that data and keep it safe.We know that there’s a lot of information here, but we want you to be fully informed about your rights, and how we use your data. We hope the following sections will answer any questions you have but if not, please do get in touch with us.1. Legal basis for processing 2. When do we collect personal data 3. The data that we collect 4. How we use your details 5. How are your details protected 6. Website users & cookies 7. The information we hold 8. How long will we keep your details 9. Who might we share your details with 10. International transfers 11. Automated decision making 12. Your rights 13. Opting out 14. Our contact details 15. The regulator 1. Legal basis for processingData protection law states there are several legal reasons why a company may collect and process personal data. We work on the following bases for certain situations: Contract – We will process your personal data to fulfil an order, deliver a service, essentially comply with our contractual obligations. An example might be, if you order a service for email delivery, we’ll collect your email address to deliver your purchase or pass them to the delivery company.Legal Compliance – If the law or government requires us to, we may need to collect and process your data. An example might be passing on details of fraud to law enforcement.Legitimate Interest – In some cases, we require personal data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way which might reasonably be expected as part of running our business. This does not impact your freedom or rights. Examples might be using postal or email details to send direct marketing information by post telling you about products and services that we think might interest you. We may also use your purchase history to send or make available personalised offers.We do not share the data that we collect directly from you with third parties for their own sales and marketing activity.Back to contents 2. When do we collect personal dataWhen you visit any of our websites or speak to an account manager on the phone.When you create a credit account with us. When you purchase a product or service by phone but don’t have (or don’t use) an account.When you engage with us on social media.When you contact us by any means with queries, complaints etc.When you enter prize draws or competitions.When you book any kind of appointment with us or book to attend an event, for example a meeting to discuss an opportunity, or an event we have organised.When you choose to complete any surveys we send you.When you comment on or review our products and services. Any individual may access personal data related to them, including opinions. So, if your comment or review includes information about the Partner who provided that service, it may be passed on to them if requested.When you’ve given a third-party permission to share with us the information they hold about you.Details that you provide us at networking events directly or where you have confirmed to the event organiser or other referring party that you are happy for your details to be shared.From publicly available sources such as Companies House, websites, industry specific directories, press releases and so on.Back to contents 3. The data we collectDetails of your interactions with us through phone contact, email or online. An example might be notes from conversations with you, complaint details, comments, purchase details and web visits.Copies of documents you provide to prove marketing compliance This will include details of your full name, work address, telephone number, ICO number, data protection contact name.Details of your visits to our websites, and which site you came from to ours.Information gathered by the use of cookies in your web browser.Payment card information. This is not stored for longer than it takes to transact.Your comments and product reviews.To deliver the best possible web experience, we collect technical information about your internet connection and browser as well as the country and telephone code where your computer is located, the web pages viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms you entered.Your social media username, if you interact with us through those channels, to help us respond to your comments, questions or feedback.Information about you that we need to manage your place and attendance on an event we have organised.Back to contents 4. How we use your detailsWe want to give you the best possible customer experience. One way to achieve that is to get the richest picture we can of who you are by combining the data we have about you. We then use this to offer you promotions, products and services that are most likely to interest you.The data privacy law allows this as part of our legitimate interest in understanding our customers and providing the highest levels of service.Of course, if you wish to change how we use your data, you’ll find details in the ‘Your rights’ which can be found in section 12.Remember, if you choose not to share your personal data with us, or refuse certain contact permissions, we might not be able to provide some services you’ve asked for.Here’s how we’ll use your personal data and why:To process any orders that you make by using our sales team. If we don’t collect your personal data during ordering, we won’t be able to process your order and comply with our legal obligations. An example may be that your details are passed to a third-party, so they can deliver your purchased product or service that you ordered. We would then keep those details for reasonable period afterwards in order to fulfil obligations such as refunds, guarantees etc.To respond to your queries, refund requests and complaints. Handling the information you sent enables us to respond. We may also keep a record of these to inform any future communication with us and to demonstrate how we communicated with you throughout. We do this on the basis of our contractual obligations to you, our legal obligations and our legitimate interests in providing you with the best service and understanding how we can improve our service based on your experience.To protect our business and your account from fraud and other illegal activities. We’ll also monitor your browsing activity with us to quickly identify and resolve any problems and protect the integrity of our websites. We’ll do all of this as part of our legitimate interest.To process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests. This also helps to protect our customers from fraud.We will use your personal data, preferences and details of your transactions to keep you informed by post, email or telephone about relevant products and services including tailored special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on.To send you communications required by law or which are necessary to inform you about our changes to the services we provide you. For example, updates to this Privacy Notice, marketing data misuse issues, and contractually required information relating to your orders. These service messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message.To administer any of our prize draws or competitions which you enter, based on your consent given at the time of entering.To develop, test and improve the systems, services and products we provide to you. We’ll do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.To comply with our contractual or legal obligations to share data with law enforcement.To send you survey and feedback requests to help improve our services. These messages will not include any promotional content and do not require prior consent when sent by email or text message.To manage your attendance on any event that we have organised that you have chosen to take part in.Of course, you are free to opt out of receiving these requests or marketing from us at any time by updating your preferences with us.Please email complianceteam@dbsdata.co.ukBack to contents 5. How are your details protectedWe will treat your data with the utmost care and take all appropriate steps to protect it.Access to personal data is limited to authorised personnel, password-protected and encrypted.We regularly monitor our systems to identify ways to further strengthen security.Physical access is limited to our premises and areas and equipment used for the storage or processing of data is further restricted to specific employees.We make use of the latest firewall technology and systems and software updates.Back to contents 6. Website users & cookiesWhat specific information is obtained? Our website does not collect specific, detailed information about you as a visitor to our site. Where information is gathered, we will inform you of this along with the explanation of why it is required.Are any payment details stored? Payment card details are used solely for individual transactions to which they have been provided for.What information is retained? Cookies and tracking software are used on a temporary basis and expire when the site has been left. These are used for purposes such as website improvement. Google Analytics is also used for the same reason of website improvement and understanding how you use it. This information is not shared with anyone.By using the website, you are consenting to the use of cookies to retain session information for the purposes listed above. This information is held in your web browser and is removed at the end of your session. The personal information we collect and hold via Tracking software is the following:Browser used (Bing, Chrome, Internet Explorer etc.)Location (based on IP address)GenderAge groupSite searchesDevice(s) usedFrequency on SiteSession duration (time spent on the site)Page(s) visitedPage session duration (time spent on specific page)Web Surfing BehavioursWe currently use the following companies that may process your personal data through website usage. Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, Google, Infusionsoft.If you need to contact us, you can find the relevant details here https://dbsdata.co.uk/enquiries/CookiesWe may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. Some of the cookies we use are essential for the site to operate.CookieNamePurposeASP.NET_Sessionid (Identifies users session on server)_aidcookieContains Affiliate ID_contact_numContact number of current person filling in the survey_cookiechecking of input if valid_egaage of user_qahashQuestion answer hash_qtValue to determine what part of the survey they are currently in_vhUnique identifier for the person who filled in the survey on the siteGoogle Analytics (uses cookies to provide meaningful reports about site visitors. They do not collect the user’s personal data)_utmaIdentifies users and sessions e.g.amount of visits (for each visitor), the time of the first visit, the previous visit and the current visit_utmbIdentifies new sessions/visits e.g. page views_utmzStores entry point into the site – the traffic source of campaign that explains how the user reached your site. E.g search engine, search keyword, link from another site etc_utmxUsed for A/B or multivariate testing using Google web optimiserPlease note that our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon you visit our site.Other WebsitesOur website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.Back to contents 7. The information we holdWe hold information about people and the businesses they work for necessary for us to conduct our business activities.Full NameJob title/functionCompany NameCompany AddressCompany Website AddressEmail AddressPhone NumberInitial RequirementTransaction historyCredit/finance historyBack to contents 8. How long will we keep your detailsFor direct marketing purposes we will keep your details and contact you while you remain a client and for up to six years from your last transaction. If you are an enquirer or prospect, we will keep your details for as long as they remain accurate and up to date. You can opt-out of receiving offers from us at any time.For accounting purposes, we will keep transactional data for at least six years and dependent upon the requirements of any applicable legislation and government agency guidance.Back to contents 9. Who might we share your details withThis information will not be shared with any organisation for their own benefit. We might share your details with contracted processors working on our behalf to deliver the products or services that you have requested, for example a company sending our own promotional material.We may have a legal obligation to share your details with organisations such as HMRC and law enforcement agencies. In this instance, we provide only the information required to perform the service. The data will only be used for that exact purpose.Partners are required to protect and respect your privacy. If we stop using a partner’s service, your data will be deleted or anonymised.Examples of third parties we work with are: • Direct marketing companies who help us manage electronic communications, social media platforms such as Google or Facebook to show products that might interest you. This is based on consent or your acceptance of cookies on our website. • Data Insight companies to ensure your details are up to date and accurate. • IT Companies who support our website and business systems. • Data Suppliers who would deliver your ordered product. • Transport and hospitality and other service providers that we use to deliver to our events.Back to contents 10. International transfersWe might transfer your details outside of the EEA for the purpose of data processing. Examples of this might include: • CRM systems • Data cleansing and validation service providers • Credit reference agencies • Data management software solution providers • Online/virtual server/back-up service providersBack to contents 11. Automated decision makingWe will not make use of your details for automated decision making.Back to contents 12. Your rightsThe right to be informed. This obligates us to tell you when we collect your details what we will do with them, how we hold them and for how long for example within a data collection notice and this privacy policy.The right of access. If you ask us, we are obliged to let you know what details we have about you.The right to rectification. You can ask us to update or change the information we hold about you.The right to erasure. You can ask us to delete or suppress your details which we will do unless there is an overriding reason that means we must keep all or part of them.The right to restrict processing. You can ask to limit the way in which we use your details.The right to data portability. You can ask us for a copy of your details in a format suitable for you to provide to another organisation.The right to object. You can object to us holding your details, or the way in which we make use of them.Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling.Back to contents 13. Opting outYou can opt out of receiving direct marketing from us by a number of different means: If we email you, click the unsubscribe link within the footer of the email. If we call you, ask our member of staff to suppress your details.If we write to you, email, call, or write to us or visit our website.complianceteam@dbsdata.co.ukCall our Compliance Officer on 01245 397 570Write to The Compliance Officer, DBS Datamarketing, 1 Buckingham Court, Dairy Road, Chelmsford CM2 6XWVisit our opt out page: http://dbsdata.co.uk/remove-my-details/Back to contents 14. Our contact details DBS Datamarketing Ltd
Registered in England & Wales 6394529 Registered with the ICO Z8475760 Registered Office: 1 Buckingham Court, Dairy Road, Chelmsford, Essex, CM2 6XW 01245 397 570Back to contents 15. The Information Commissioner’s OfficeInformation Commissioner’s Office Wycliffe House Water Lane Wilmslow Cheshire SK9 5AFHelpline number: 0303 123 1113 www.ico.org.ukIf you are based outside the UK, please contact the relevant data protection regulator in your country.Policy Updated – 27th March 2019Back to contents CONTACT USTo request a callback or register your interest please complete the details below:
Name*
Company Name*
Contact No*
Email*
Comments
Preferred Call Back Time
8am9am10am11amMidday1pm2pm3pm4pm5pm6pm7pm8pm
Where did you hear about us?
GoogleYahooOther search engineThe DMAListlinkEmail from DBSPrevious contact from DBSReferred SENDHow will we use your information?We will use the information that you are providing here to enable us to respond to your request and deliver our services to you.  We will also add your details to our secure CRM system to help us manage our relationship with you as it develops. This means that we will be able to send you newsletters and details about our products and services that we think will be relevant and of interest to you. We’ll keep your information safe and secure and we won’t share your details with anyone else without asking you first.  We might use third party companies to process your information on our behalf, for example cloud based software or post or email distribution companies if we are sending you a newsletter. Of course, you can always opt out any time, just let us know. Please visit our privacy policy for a more detailed look at how we manage personal information.01245 397 570Send us an emailDBS Datamarketing Ltd 1 Buckingham Court Dairy Road Chelmsford Essex CM2 6XW
Registered in England and Wales 6394529. Registered Office: 1 Buckingham Court, Dairy Road, Chelmsford, Essex. CM2 6XW Registered with The Information Commissioner’s Office. Data Protection Registration Number Z8475760
This site uses cookies. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. Learn moreOkay, thank you
